[Music]
hello and a very warm welcome to all of
you on this special episode of world
hard day IC Lombard presents D say
partnered by ET now now heart attack and
stroke are words that are not unknown
anymore the number of people suffering
from cardiovascular diseases has been
rapidly increasing over the past few
years with an estimated 54 5 million in
India alone suffering from it globally
520 million people are living with
cardiovascular diseases and covid-19 has
further added to their V because many
have been afraid to attend routine and
emergency appointments because they are
worried and they are scared that they
would contract the virus this has in
turn also LED people to become isolated
from friends and families now this
Healthcare crisis has made it urgent to
find different and innovative ways to
connect people to heart health
particularly among the lower resource
population and on This World Heart Day
September 29th times Network along with
ICI Lombard is trying to find out the
causes that make one prone to cardiac
ailments over the years the role of
health insurance in protection and
rebuilding the hearts and what we can do
to protect ourselves and to save our
hearts I we have two special experts
joining us on this panel allow me to
introduce them we have Mr bhavas Gupta
he's the MD at ICI Lombard General
insurance and we also have padmabhushan
and padmashri aardi Dr Ashok s the
chairman at Fortis escorts Heart
Institute gentlemen thank you so much
for joining me here today Dr s I'd like
to start with you first up Sir um
despite the increasing awareness around
heart health number of cardiovascular
diseases people suffering from
cardiovascular diseases is increasing at
an alarming rate globally as well as in
India how can one be more aware and
vigilant for early signs and to prevent
a serious situation you're so right
Sumit uh India's become the heart attack
capital of the world uh to tell you
frankly deaths from heart disease in the
west have decreased by 50% decreased by
50% in the last 30 years deaths from
heart disease in India have increased
300% in the last 30 years three times
the incidence of corne arries and as a
race we got to understand that we more
prone to have heart disease uh we are
three times more prone than Europeans
for the same risk factors by way for
similar risk factors three times more
prone than Europeans six time more prone
than Chinese and 20 times more than
Japanese to have heart disease so in
know as as so we practically as a race
we are loaded guns who could actually
develop heart disease if the
circumstances became in unfavorable to
each of us and that's why both for men
and women heart disease has become the
biggest killer it used to be 10 years
ago infections but now it's the heart
disease for both men and women so yes
and that reason one of the other big
concerns I must point out is that over
the last 15 years heart disease in young
individuals mean which means people less
than 50 has actually increased
200% that's last 15 years so these are
worrying worrying
statistics especially when we think that
50% of population is Youth and if
they're getting affected by heart
disease at an early age what's going to
happen in 10 years and 15 years 20 years
and of course we can discuss why this
has happened but we have to face the
reality and that's why this program the
messaging to people how to prevent heart
disease how to control it has become
equally important absolutely and Dr said
I will come back to you on those
important points because it's like
almost like we're sitting on a ticking
bomb in this sense I will come back to
you on that in a second I just want to
go over to uh Mr Das Gupta so you know
and in my intro I said this that it is
that the pandemic has an had has had an
impact on everyone across the globe but
how has it impacted the health insurance
industry specifically well suit you're
right this is something that uh
obviously has affected the whole world
and when you look at Insurance uh
Insurance model really works in a
situation where a lot of people
contribute small amounts to create an
insurance pool and a few people have an
accident or a damage or a health event
and a large amount is paid out for each
one of them that's how the insurance
model works so when there's a pandemic
that becomes a real challenge for the
industry now if you look at what's
happened for our industry given the wave
1 and the wave two that we've just
recently seen uh the industry's taken a
hit of uh already more than 30,000
crores this was never expected or priced
to our product so that's been one
immediate uh adverse impact that we've
had as an industry and by the way as an
industry unlike most industries that got
affected we've not gone back to anyone
asking for you know any any support from
the government or anyone else so that's
one negative the at the same time U you
know in one way it has increased the
awareness of health insurance and if you
look at the uh the uh the research that
people are doing about health care and
health insurance they that's SE a
significant
and if you see see consequently the
demand for health insurance has
increased very rapidly if you look at
the last you know 18 on months health
insurance has grown at about 35% in
terms of the premium collection so while
the first is a huge negative from a
short-term perspective the second is in
the long term potentially a positive the
third thing that has happened that we
are observing is that people are
realizing the importance of buying
proper cover in the past people would
buy a three lak cover or four lakh cover
which people realized that for for a
whole family that's not enough so we are
seeing upgradation in terms of the
summon sh that people are buying and
last and I think this is probably the
most important uh change that we are
seeing is the uh the health seeking
behavior for customers are changing and
people are getting more comfortable with
digital Health uh tele Health uh you
know virtual doctors and seeking those
Services Beyond just you know
hospitalization when when some big
episode happens so we are seeing
multiple changes uh you know the whole
Paradigm of health insurance you know
largely driven by this Pand Dr s you
know for an average adult how much of
exercise of physical activity is
sufficient to keep cardiovascular
disease at day because you know
sedentary lifestyle is said to be one of
the major causes of heart attacks your
thoughts on that exercise is one area
which actually controls a lot of things
within your body for example if I told
you that 45 minutes of exercise with a
five minute warm-up and a five minute
cool down five times a week decreases
our chances of Heart Attack by 20%
that's huge because it controls our
weight it actually people who actually
exercise their blood pressure comes
under control if they have diabetes that
comes under control it actually gives a
sense of wellbeing people who are you
know wanting to be fit give up smoking
they actually want to exercise better
and it gives a sense of positivity so it
actually takes care of all the factors
including stress exercise takes care of
that as well and so importantly is this
fact that it cannot be compared to
jimming yes if jimming in World on the
treadmill aerobic exercises aerobic
exercises are great for the heart but
yes the youth today wants to go to gyms
to build up muscles to build up fatigue
look goodness there's nothing wrong with
that but the the the the important
aspect to realize this that is not
necessarily heart health heart health
revolves around aerobic exercises
getting the heart rate to a particular
level and then going down and jimming is
a is is for physical fitness of muscle
building for perhaps running 10
kilometers is not necessarily great for
the heart it may be good for stamina it
may be good for weight loss but may not
necessarily be any better for the heart
Dr said I just want to take this one
step ahead you were mentioning this also
but about the diet so any suggestions
that you have about maintaining a
healthy hard diet so that you know we're
eating right and keeping our heart
healthy through nutrition through right
nutrition those who have high blood
pressure diabetes of course they need to
be careful about the carbohydrates
intake maintain diabetes under good
control and maintain blood pressure
under good control and take less of
Salish food apart from that I would say
that we into diet fats at the moment
actually the balanced diet the most
nourishing diet is the balanced diet
without any extremes
where you actually take the evening meal
much earlier than than later so you you
know you finish your Meals by 7
8:00 and if they homecooked meals which
are normally cooked in the usual oils
the healthy oils then there's nothing to
exclude from the diet the key word is
balanced diet there uh Mr Das Gupta I
just want to come to you on another
point that we were talking about is uh
so coming back to the impact of the
pandemic now obvious ly uh for people
health insurance is important otherwise
also the pandemic has made it even more
important and people are more aware
about it now but I know that your
organization one of the important steps
during the pandemic was to keep
communicating with customers what are
some of the initiatives that were taken
by cic Lombard to support customers
during the covid-19 pandemic well Sumit
you know like everyone else we were also
affected as individuals right so we had
to also go into a lockdown right in the
beginning you know all of us were
but thankfully over the years we had
invested heavily in terms of a digital
infrastructure and that helped us in
this period in terms of communication so
we took a lot of effort in the first
month you know back in April 2020 in
terms of digitally communicating with
our distribution as also our our
customers but very soon thereafter we
realized that there were certain other
features that we needed to offer first
was that even before the uh the
regulator asked the industry to uh you
know consider issuing a covid specific
policy we launched one uh you know
usually in a pandemic environment as I
explained it's very difficult to launch
a health insurance or any insurance
product it's like you know giving
Insurance to someone whose house is
burning so in a pandemic the situation
is is something like that but we felt
that it was our responsibility as a
company to launch a covid specific
product thereafter what we did was for a
standard products the normal Indemnity
hospitalization plans we said uh not
only will we cover covid treatment for
hospitalization we also said that you
know the waiting period which is usually
30-day waiting period we said we'll
reduce it to 15 days for covid because
again you know it was a it was a crisis
for our customers we said we need to do
that for our customers third thing that
we did for on the product side was to
say that when you claim on a covid uh
inent you know because it's a pandemic
we will not take away the benefit that
you have for no non- claim right so we
have a equivalent of a no claim bonus
called additional sum insured so if you
don't claim for a year then next to the
some insured goes up we said if you have
a covid incident we will not uh you know
reduce the some insur next year
thereafter what we realized was the
customers were actually seeking
different types of you know service in
the sense that as I said digital Health
you know healthcare service so we said
that customers were worried about going
to hospitals at this point in time for
other uh ailments so we launched a T
Health Service we had the capability but
we started giving it out for our normal
customers you know to telec Consulting
free normally it's a price product for
people who buy that cup but we gave it
out to to our customers for free and
then we launched you know homebased
Healthcare again you know people are
afraid of going to hospitals we said on
a cashless basis we wanted it to be
cashless so that we could ensure the
quality of treatment and the fact that
we were aware of the the protocol was as
per you know doctor's protocol so we
launch a cashless home health benefit so
there's been multiple initiative that we
did uh you know very soon after the
pandemic hit us on that note it's time
for a very short break here on this
special World hard day show ICI Lombard
presents D say partnered by ET now don't
go anywhere we'll be right
[Music]
back welcome back to IC Lombard presents
D say partnered by ET now it's a very
special show that we're doing on the
occasion of world hard day I'm joined by
two speak Mr bab Das Gupta the MD at ICI
Lombard General insurance and
padmabhushan and padmashri award Dr
Ashok shet he's the chairman at Forst
escorts Art Institute Dr Sate you know
in my opinion and you're the expert so I
would love to hear from you on this it's
really important that laymen everyday
common people should be aware of first
aid skills if someone around them is
having a heart attack all of a sudden
what's the first thing that we should do
because by the time help arrives if
there are some simple things that we can
do it can help people if you could guide
us on that there are certain cities in
the west like Seattle where the public
has actually been trained to deal with
such situations and resuscitate people
with actually multiple lives being saved
in the city because every public every
person or majority of the people know
how to resuscitate we call it
cardiopulmonary resuscitation now it's
not too difficult to learn and many
centers have started training and
teaching public around this but if
someone drops and this could happen in
our own family it could happen to our
friends it could happen to even in a
mall as we walking if somebody just
collapses the first thing to is to lie
him down flat that's the first thing
secondly to understand whether he's
breathing or not
breathing thirdly at the same time he
say call for help right which means call
an ambulance service call a police
service but immediately tell someone to
call that police MH the fourth thing we
do is make sure his head is pulled back
so that his tongue doesn't drop in and
therefore he's breathing give you know
many people start giving water at that
time that's a bad thing because the
person may be unconscious and therefore
you may actually put water and that may
go into the lungs so the main thing is
to keep his Airways open so we call it
Airways open which means tilt his head
backwards so that his tongue doesn't
drop on his Airway the fifth thing is
give him a big thump on the chest
when heart when when these sudden heart
attacks or arrhythmias occur and cause
sudden collapse a single thumb to the
chest May restore the Rhythm back to
normal and so it's a single thump to the
chest and finally as you seek help you
make sure you're not lying in the middle
of the road you're actually somewhere
which is safe for you and the patient
your second help actually push put Tils
the head back and you just start
compressing the center of the chest
right here at a rate of 70 per minute so
that you actually restore as much
circulation to the brain as possible as
long as you continue that briskly you
will be able to maintain a person till
the health arrive for a period of a few
minutes and those few minutes are the
vital ones which you need to maintain
the individual absolutely thank you so
much for that Dr say that is really
really key uh for for for other I I just
wanted to to tell you that we used to
talk about the mouth to mouth
respiration Al at the same time it is
not essential what is essential is
keeping the areas open and actually
pressing the chest and of course in
these days of covid we also want to
emphasize that is pressing the chest
Which is far more important than than
mouth to mouth respirations absolutely
thank you so much for highlighting these
really important points U Mr Das Gupta
you know uh just taking this point ahead
World Heart Day is here it's a really
important day in the calendar especially
for India and Dr sh has also spoken
about what what our scenario here is uh
any specific offerings from IC Lombard
for World Heart Day for for people out
here so there are you know multiple
things that we are doing but before I
get into what we're doing I think it's
important to explain the philosophy that
we are building the health insurance
model on I think Global research shows
that the entire effort on preventive uh
for you know normal consumers and
disease management for people at risk
leads to tremendous benefit for the
consumers in terms of lower incidents of
hospitalization I mean there are
research that shows that even for uh you
know high-risk patients if you manage
the preventive and the disease
management well the incident rates drop
by you know 20 to
30% so our entire effort has been to
focus on this entire wellness and the
preventive uh side so we have an app uh
called I take care app which focuses on
these aspects along with normal
Insurance Services uh and this this app
was launched before covid but has really
picked up you know in the last 18 months
today we have more than 8 and a half
lakh downloads of this app now here
we've kind of focused on some of these
you know wellness and preventive
Services uh one of the things that we've
done specifically as a as you know as a
as a launch in this period was uh a
calorie counter because one of the
things that we've realized is that among
many features of you know wellness and
benefit diet plays a very important role
and we've had nutritionists and you know
health coaches Etc which were available
but we have added a calorie counter uh
so you can you know scan your items and
you can you know count the calories the
other thing that we've done is uh you
know multiple types of products so what
I talked about is is service we also
looked at products Dr s I want to talk
to you now about the important role of
Technology because uh we know that
technology has been a great help during
covid-19 in every sector every industry
especially tele medicine uh your
thoughts on how we can use this to cater
to regular needs and medical
investigation for cardiovascular
diseases and your opinion that where
does India's Health Care System stand
considering today's technological
Advanced world where are we headed to
your thoughts India is perhaps there are
more cell phones in India uh than
anywhere else in the world so that's an
important aspect our prime minister
himself is talking about even as of
today 5G um and and uh Wi-Fi for all in
this country which is a great step
forwards and once we see that we know
that a lot of monitoring a lot of
realtime help can be given by remote
monitoring there's also real-time ECG
monitoring but artificial intelligence
is coming in hugely as an interface
between the patient and the doctor to
start immediately advising him look this
is abnormal we think you should take
take an extra tablet by the time your
doctor answers you or for example look
at the ECG this is your realtime ECG we
think that this ECG suddenly changed
abnormal we think you should contact a
doctor so artificial intelligence can
even do a lot of help to the doctor by
removing that lag time between the time
real time monitoring where the P where
the patient cannot see the abnormality
but artificial intelligence can see an
abnormality and transfer it to the
patient and give the give give the
patient an advice and yet transfer it to
the doctor to to decrease the lag phase
fantastic that's a great uh leap for
Innovation which is definitely going to
make a big uh Mark and provide a lot of
help to people uh just as we wind up one
last question to Mr Das Gupta so what
are some of the new product launches
from IC Lombard that we can expect to
see soon or that have been recently
launched by the organization you're
right in the sense that heart ailment
creates significant uh you know
Financial impact and if you look at the
prevalence of heart disease it's really
even you know between uh the young age
group of let's say up to 20 to 49 uh one
in seven uh people suffer you know heart
ailment it's a very high number and
we've launched a critical illness plan
which covers 200 different uh you know
critical illnesses including heart with
a lot of features in terms of Lifetime
coverage so even multiple claims uh you
know reset benefits Etc so so there are
multiple features that we've launched
lastly as I said the entire Journey for
us is to provide endtoend healthare a
Continuum of Care starting with
preventive to critical care so on that
we've launched a bit product where you
can actually get cashless OPD service
all of these features in terms of you
know health coach Wellness guidance
nutrition uh Etc plus if you
unfortunately need to get treated there
is a you know network of you know
General Practitioners Pharmacy chains uh
diagnostic Centers so not just
hospitalization even for
non-hospitalization you can get those uh
you know covers on our on our app so
these are some of the uh products and
services that we've launched around the
world world hard Dr St as we wind up
this episode just wanting your closing
comments any message that you want to
leave our viewers with on the occasion
of World Heart Day firstly of course
I've always said that prevention of
heart disease protection from heart
attacks is in your hands and in fact
it's not just in your hands it's
actually in your feet it doesn't require
great Investments it just requires
sports shoes is what you by and the
roads on which you walk and you decrease
your heart attack so that's the first
thing in fact it takes lesser uh it's
it's it's least expensive to decrease
heart attacks because you eat healthy
you don't actually eat out you actually
give up smoking and you save money so
everything that you do to prevent heart
disease saves you money and the and the
second aspect I would say is prevention
prevention prevention if you have risk
factors if anyone or I have risk factors
which means smoking or diabetes or
hypertension and I have a strong family
history where someone in my family has
heart had a heart attack at a young age
or passed away suddenly at a young age I
must start my checkups as early as the
age of 20 or 25 and have regular
checkups from the doctors so that early
signs can be picked up initially and
preventive measures put in so that the
same fate which happened to say our Clos
near and dear relatives do not happen to
us prevention goes along on those lines
regular checkup and taking your own
personal actions those two are important
stay well stay healthy save your heart
that's the most important message
absolutely thank you so much Dr s for
that that was really beautifully put uh
so thank you so much my one message to
everyone would be that our most
cherished asset is our health and this
is something that has come home very
very uh starkly to all of us in this
period so do take care of yourself do
take care of your heal
take care of your heart well that's all
the time that we have today on this
special show IC Lombard presents B say
partnered by ET now where we were
talking to Mr bhavas Gupta the MD at ICC
lombar General insurance and also to
padmabhushan and padmashri awarde Dr
Ashok shet the chairman of forus escorts
Heart Institute on the special occasion
of World Heart Day thank you so much for
watching stay safe and stay healthy
[Music]